Erdni Zergetaev

zergetaev@gmail.com 89962590913 Uchinskaya 3, apt 111 Moscow

Summary

Fullstack developer with 5 years of expertise in Ruby on Rails, Node.js (Express.js) & React/Redux. Self-motivated, organized and reliable. Worked on both startups that use bleeding-edge tech and huge websites with millions of users and legacy code. Can work great in teams, especially if using Agile.

Other major skills include: PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Webpack, SCSS, GraphQL (Apollo), TypeScript, Docker, Capistrano.

Open to remote jobs, contracts and visa sponsorship proposals.

Employment History

Remote fullstack developer

Busbud • Montreal, Quebec

08/2019 - Present

Busbud is the world's largest bus ticket seller.

Responsibilities: adding a support for selling train tickets and adaption for russian audience.

Used technologies: ES6, TypeScript, Node.JS, Express.js, React.js/Redux, Jest, PostgreSQL, Docker.

Remote fullstack developer

Vayable • San Francisco, California

05/2019 - 08/2019

Building a new iteration of a popular travel platform with Ruby on Rails, React.js, Redux and JSON:API.

Full stack developer

Krypton Capital

12/2017 - 05/2019

Projects:

https://jury.online/ - a platform for safe ICO investments. During my tenure the project has successfully raised more than 3 million dollars in investments.

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Develop a web interface for Ethereum smart contract. Work directly with Solidity developers to integrate smart contracts via Metamask Browser extension.
- Develop a JSON API with accompanying Swagger documentation.
- Replace an old frontend (CoffeeScript, jQuery and Bower) with a more modern ES6, React.js & Webpack solution. Integrate it with Rails using Webpacker gem.
- Participate in the discussions of the overall platform architecture & user experience. We have been able to seriously reduce the complexity of user interface in the latest versions by automizing a lot of the mundane tasks.
- Improve Rspec test coverage to 90%

Selected Accomplishments:

Jury.online was way behind the schedule for the start of the ICO. I was brought in to speed up the development of a demo version of the platform, and I have succeeded, helping the project to raise more than 3 million dollars in ETH investments.

Technologies used:

- · Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL
- Bootstrap 4
- · React.js
- Web3.js
- · Metamask Chrome extension
- Bower
- Webpack
- jQuery
- Rspec
- Capybara
- EcmaScript 6

https://buzz.im/ - a platform for advertising in Telegram messenger.

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Develop an ad exchange catalogue that needs to work fast (via Rails caching) and not to lose any of the concurrent transactions (via Pessimistic ActiveRecord locking)
- Work with the developers of telegram bot (@buzz_im_bot) to integrate its capabilities into the platform
- Develop a JSON API with accompanying Swagger documentation, which is used by the new frontend written in Vue.js.
- Work with with designers on mockups for a design revamp, integrate the resulting HTML & CSS into the platform.
- Help the marketing department with their job by improving SEO and creating helpful metrics with Metabase.

Technologies used:

- · Ruby on Rails 5
- MySQL
- Bootstrap 4
- StimulusIS
- Webpack
- jQuery
- Rspec
- Capybara
- EcmaScript 6

https://spika.org - a popular russian concert agency.

Technologies used:

- · Ruby on Rails 5
- PostgreSQL
- · Bootstrap 4

- Webpack
- jQuery
- · Vue.js

Fullstack web developer

Freelancer 02/2016 - 12/2017

Worked as a freelance Ruby on Rails developer under a guidance of senior Ruby on Rails developer from Zillow Group.

Gained experience working with modern web development technologies and techniques, through the development of B2B solution built with Ruby on Rails 4, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL and ReactJS.

Professional Skills

- · Rails
- Express.js
- TypeScript
- Linux
- Git
- · Capistrano
- Node.js
- Node.jsBootstrap

- React
- Redux
- PostgreSQL
- Rspec
- Docker
- Jquery
- GraphQL
- Stimulus.js

Education

IT

Kalmyk State University • Elista, Kalmykia Republic

06/2017

Languages

· Russian: Native

· Kalmyk: Conversational

· English